has a lane 1510 touchdown
Chargers.
>> What's up, guys? Welcome in to Chargers
Weekly, a special edition. The draft
class is complete. Joined by the voice
of the Chargers, Matt Money Smith, doing
this from home after hosting the big
party at the Bolt. How was that, man?
>> It was great, man. Both fam turnout.
Talk about a turnout. I'd say a couple
thousand would be my guess. just kind of
eyeballing it and people standing in
line for quite a while and you know I
applaud them for for being patient but
they were doing tours of the Bolt and
the line wrapped Chris you know the Bolt
I I hope enough of the people listening
kind of know it but figure I don't know
what do you think that front parking lot
is 200 spaces maybe so it went from the
front door
>> all the way to the back of the parking
lot right by the street there and then
wrapped all the way back up to that
entry driveway that is how long people
were waiting to go take the tour Um they
did autographs, interviewed Tyler
Bottes, Arande Gadston, Akeem Meador, uh
everyone got to take some photos, people
that stood in line, you know, they did
about 20-minute window there where we
get stuff signed, take some photos, uh
food trucks, and it was it was And then
Los Lobos played, which was just
incredible. You know, one of the great
East LA bands, Los Angeles bands, you
know, that if you're of a certain age,
you certainly felt uh you know, their
influence on you. And and it was a
really cool event. And again, just
salute to all the folks I talked to that
love Chargers Weekly. Got that pretty
much everything everyone I talked to.
That was the first thing that came up.
Chris, where's Chris? I talked to him.
Uh or uh Mikey's Mikey D's dad said that
he talked to you and was bummed that you
weren't there, but a lot of people were
asking me where you were, so you were
his brother.
>> Yeah. Yeah.
>> Yeah. Mark's Mark's a great dude. Uh I
got the same in uh in Pittsburgh, man.
People at the airport, loves Chargers
Weekly, and I just I love doing it with
you, dude. It's it's been a fun weekend
and we we have so much to talk about.
I'm so glad the Chargers did the party
on a Saturday, too. That way, Messador
is there. You see what happened
yesterday with Slaughter. Your interview
with Chad was incredible. Uh just some
great insight into who Slaughter is and
just kind of how they approach that
draft process. And then today, man, like
so one of the things that kind of stuck
in my mind that I think multiple like
draft analysts have told us is, you
know, the top 15, top 20 pretty set from
20 to like you name it, hundred. like
anybody could go anywhere and when the
Chargers kept trading back it just led
me to believe that the guys that they
coveted the most were still on the
board. So there you're able to to acrew
uh AC crew picks sorry phrasing there.
Um Brennan Thompson at the beginning of
round four.640
a speedster Mike McDaniel written all
over it right.
>> Yeah no doubt. Um, I I'll say like the
just for people that might not have
watched the the presser, but uh the way
Joe Hortiz described it was that when
they recon after doing all the
tradebacks and picking up seven picks um
when you know they reconvened after the
press conference that they had and and
like you said, we had a chance to talk
to Chad on the pod last night. So, if
you haven't listened to that, be sure
you listen to that cuz it's pretty fun
listening to them and kind of seeing
where everything went here today. Um,
that they listed seven players that, you
know, they have their buckets and they
have their verticals and all that, but
they had a list of seven players on top
of the board that they really wanted to
try to get. And that was kind of what of
all the players they had left that they
determined would be potential draft
picks for him, seven of them really
stood out. And of their six picks that
they made, because of course they traded
up for one of them, um they got four and
one of them was a blue star. So, um Nick
Barrett was a blue star. And I can see
why, man. I did not watch um many
defensive interior defensive linemen. I
just didn't wasn't sure kind of. It's
just it's a lot to take on when you're
trying to do all these positions.
Sometimes you sacrifice them. So, I did
not watch Nick Barrett as soon as he was
drafted.
Man, I'm telling you, I don't know what
this team has got, Chris, on interior
defensive linemen, on defensive tackles,
but they can do it. They can do it. And
whether it's Caldwell or the guys
they're signing like Puna and Thiier and
Deshawn Hand and now Tomlinson or it's
you know Jamari Caldwell like I said
like this guy I don't know how in the
heck he slipped to the fifth round cuz
we were watching Popper and I were
watching the um Texas A&M game and he is
wrecking Chase Basantis this game
wrecking him. I mean wrecking him. It
was wild to watch. Then we dig deeper
and we're just like, "What the hell?
Where did this guy like So, so that's of
all the picks that were made today. You
I'll you know, you can get into Brendan
Thompson here because I know you got a
lot on that, but like that was um and he
was a scout's blue star. So, for people
that don't know what that means, Joe
mentioned yesterday that Jake Slaughter
was his blue star. Each person gets one
blue star. This is this is the player
I'm putting my name on. this is who I
want, you know, and and and who I don't
remember Chad. I couldn't remember who
Chad said it was. It was one of the
scouts, but uh it was his blue star. And
man, I got to find out which scout it
was because I want to make sure I shake
his hand because man, did that tape get
me excited.
>> Nick Barrett, uh teammates with Kyle
Canard a couple of years ago, too. So,
you get two two Gamecocks on the uh the
defensive line. Uh dude, there's so many
guys we can get into like Brennan
Thompson. How about the Travis Burke uh
draft? Nobody's bigger than Joe Alt
except for Travis Burke. Travis Burke is
bigger than Joe Alt. Uh another uh you
know, we talk so much about interior
offensive line, but there's a real
concern about the depth on the outside.
Trey Pipkins is your swing tackle, but
you bring in another guy who can
develop. Um and when you hear mean and
nasty and violent associated with an
offensive lineman, that's exactly what
Jim Harbaugh wants. Money. Man, look,
Trey Pipkins was the swing tackle last
year, right? And last time I checked, we
called games with Trevor Penning, Austin
Deculus, Bobby Hart at tackle. So for
people like for and this happened a lot
and and I love it because it's passion
and it's just it's love for your team
and I think it comes from a good place,
but so many people were like, "Talk me
off the ledge. Why what's up with guard?
Why can't like it goes beyond guard? You
can't just focus on that one position
because last year, like I said, think
about Bobby Hart playing tackle in that
Houston game, Austin Deculus playing
tackle. I think that was the Indie game.
Like, you need to avoid those
situations. Those are losses in games
because you didn't have enough depth.
And and as coach Harbaugh said after the
the draft, you know, concluded in his
presser in in the Chad Joe uh coach
Harbaugh presser, he said going into the
draft, we had or he said on the last day
of the season last year, we had three
offensive linemen under contract. Three.
Today we've got 14.
>> 14.
>> So they attacked it. what whatever you
want and impregn this and basantis that
and rutled this and dunker that. They
have 14 offensive linemen under contract
right now and that is a great
improvement from where they were at the
end of last season.
>> By the way, they didn't have a backup
center. So, you know, those confused
about Jake Slaughter, I don't know why
you're confused because Jake Slaughter
is going to be the future center of the
Chargers. Um, you know, it's it's great
to have Tyler Bottish here for the next
couple of years and um maybe beyond. But
it's it's good to have depth too at that
position. One of the most important
positions uh on the offensive line on
the offense period.
>> Well, they think he's a guard, Chris.
I'll just say that like I I because
because I asked last night when I was
talking with Chad and and they're like,
"Oh, no. We we think he's a guard."
>> They announced him as a guard. They
announced him as a guard. And so I I
have no doubt that he'll he could be the
the starting left guard. Um, the only
pause I have about it now is that you
bring in Logan Taylor and Alex Harky and
we know competitors are always welcome,
right? Coyotes in the in the building.
Uh, Trevor Penning actually played
pretty decent at guard with the Saints.
Uh, he didn't get to get an opportunity
much to play guard here at the Chargers
because of the tackle issues. Yeah. So,
the the the competitors welcome mantra
rings very true this off seasonason and
training camp. It's going to be a lot of
fun actually to watch these guys compete
in preseason games um in the joint
practices. Uh, but you're right. Like as
soon as Slaughter Slaughter was
announced by Marryman as a guard, I was
like, "There it is. They're gonna
they're gonna uh make him the guard."
And I know that there was some some talk
about some of his reps at the Senior
Bowl weren't that great, but
>> not good.
>> Yeah.
>> Not good.
>> But are you So, what do you think? Are
you thinking that this is a Mike
McDaniel offensive line scheme match?
Right. His athleticism
>> I think the idea he's super athletic. um
really he can really move and so I think
it's a projection and it's a let's get
you know Butch Barry and Nick Hardwick
working with him and and he's incredibly
smart. Uh I've talked to a few different
people in the building last night after
and I just said hey look man I didn't I
didn't see that at all. I I thought Sam
Heck could be a a center to guard guy.
Um I didn't see it with Slaughter. just
kind of walked me through it and they,
you know, basically said, "Look, he's
crazy smart. He's just he sees it." And
and by smart, I'm sure he's fine
generally. He's an intelligent person,
but football smart. Like, this is a guy
that sees things materialize before they
materialize. He's that kind of football
savvy smart. And so when we think about
stuff that we talked about last year,
you know, with Zion, like, hey, the
stunts, the vision, Bradley Boseman just
flat out missing guys and you got wide
open paths to the quarterback. Like that
does not happen with this guy. And so I
think that's sort of the foundation of
it. And then on top of that, you build
the athleticism, the movement skills.
Um, and the hope is that you can you can
make it all work at guard because he can
see it. And um and so I think that's
their vision. Now, will it work? I don't
know. You know, they tried to make Zion
a center, didn't work. They tried to
make Branson Taylor a guard. Work in
progress. We'll see. So, I'm not going
to pretend like there's an answer to
that that's a definitive no. You don't
know. But, as you said, Chris, and I
think it's a it's a perfect, you know,
observation is they could not go into
the season with with Coltonber as their
backup center. That's not that's that's
not a viable option. So they had to get
a backup center. We were talking about
it. Do you draft Logan Jones in the
third? Do you draft, you know, heck in
the third? Like we that was a
conversation we had on a prior Chargers
weekly. So I think this is sort of a
hey, worst case scenario. He's our
backup center
>> and we'll figure it out from there.
>> Sorry. They got their consensus guy too,
right? It was it was Joe's blue star
guy. Everybody in that room seemed like
Jake Slaughter was their guy, no doubt,
as a center who could who could also be
a guard. So, I I can't wait to see those
battles in camp. And yeah,
>> I don't I money did I didn't get to see
like the last five 10 minutes of of uh
Cortiz and and Harbaugh. Did they
address veteran guard at all after the
draft? Did they say that that's a
possibility?
>> They were asked about
>> they were asked about corner in the
veteran market because they did not
draft a corner and I felt like that was
a position that could have been
addressed in the draft. So, they were
asked about that and they basically made
a blanket statement of yes, once the
draft concludes and we get all of our
free agents, undrafted college free
agent, college free agents squared away,
yes, that will, you know, we'll dip back
into that market and and see what it
looks like. But, I mean, there was no
there was no declarative statement of,
yeah, we're going to go out there and
No, I look, I know fans may not want to
hear this. Uh, and it's just me kind of
reading the tea leaves. Um, and I could
be wrong and maybe they will go, but I I
think just if you look at the profile of
Trevor Penning, he does kind of fit what
Mike McDaniel likes. He's very athletic.
Um, he can move, you know, and and I
thought he excelled in that sixth
offensive lineman role when you're asked
to move a lot and and get after it. And
so I think if you just kind of look at
it through that lens, like, hey, what
kind of offensive lineman? And obviously
he's huge compared to, you know, the
smaller guys that that outside zone you
typically see playing offensive line,
but but he moves for a big man. And so I
do think if they went to to Butch Barry
and Mike McDaniel said, "Hey, how do you
feel about Trevor? What do you you know
what you see? Can you work with this?" I
think he probably said, "Yeah, I can
work with that." Um, and I think that
may have sort of eased where they were
coming from um, a little bit, but then
again, 50% of their picks were offensive
line. So, they had eight picks and you
got um, 50 four Yeah, four of them.
Exactly. Four of them are offensive
line. So, and if all that does is build
depth and you get guys in the building
that you can coach up and you can
actually have viable backups where
you're not signing guys off the street
and off practice squads that got to come
in on Monday and play the following
Sunday, like then they've they've done a
great service. And so, I think with
Logan Taylor and and Alex Harky, they
both are guard tackle flexible. And I
think that's what you noticed with if
they think that Jake Slaughter is center
guard flexible, then you got three guys
that they think, you know, can play
multiple positions along the offensive
line. And so I think those are good
depth pieces. Um they really like uh I
was talking to someone and talking about
Logan Taylor and and they're like he's
got he's got legitimate potential, like
legitimate starting potential. Um, so
there's Look, I think I said this last
night and um and I guess I'll just say
it again like if if Pregnon
Everybody got so fixated on Pregnon. If
Pregnon was that great of a prospect
that Keelin Rutled was taken in the
first round and Houston traded up to get
him and Chase Basantis was one of the
first five picks in the second round and
Vega Yuane went 14 overall when Ruben
Bane was on the board for Baltimore.
Like that's how important some of these
teams valued guard. To see Dunker and
Pregnon slide all the way to the back
end of the third round tells you kind of
media consensus board be damned. I don't
care what the media consensus board is.
That tells you what the NFL consensus
board was. That players at a position
that seemed to be at a premium for the
premium players, Basantis, Rutlidge,
Yani, and where they went allowed those
two guys that everybody was talking to
me about in the lot about how upset they
were that they didn't get Pregnon, you
know, they slid. They slid past what
would have been the Chargers third round
pick. Um, and so look, can Pregnon be a
great player? Sure. Bes and so could
Dunker. They could end up being great
and and that's fine. But I think
evaluations
are unique to each team. And I'm not
going to question, you know, Joe who was
in Baltimore where they drafted Ronnie
Stanley and Tyler Linderbomb and and
Jonathan Ogden and all of those guys. is
if it's his blue star guy and he thinks
he can play guard, then I'm going to
give him the benefit of the doubt, you
know, and if it doesn't happen, then we
can have that conversation. But I'm
going to give that guy the benefit of
the doubt.
>> Also, you when we had that conversation
with Mike McDaniel after he was
introduced and we we talked about his
just him majoring in the running game,
he knows what he wants. He knows what he
wants. He he has evaluated everybody on
this roster. He's told you what he
thinks about Cole Strange. Um, he he's
told you what he thinks about Tyler
Bottish. They brought him in and I have
to believe that he was on board with
Jake Slaughter. I saw him high-fiving
Chris Oir right after the pick. So,
yeah. Um, how about we give Mike
McDaniel uh the benefit of the doubt and
Butch Barry the benefit of the doubt
here. Greg Roman had his offense, his
scheme, the guys that he liked. Let's
have Mike McDaniel just take a crack at
it as well. And one of the questions
that you posed to Chad last night that I
thought was great and it actually kind
of dovetailed into something I saw last
night with Eric Dcasta talking about um
just taking more cracks, getting more
swings, um acrewing more picks. It
allows you to, you know, maybe hit on a
guy like you know if if they didn't have
that extra pick or those extra picks
today, money, I don't know if they would
have taken two guards in the sixth
round, but they had extra picks, right?
So, you have Logan Taylor, who you
mentioned his his starter potential,
Alex Harky, and then, you know, to get a
guy like Nick Barrett, who you just
raved about, Genesis Smith, who, you
know, the ding is is the tackling, but
yeah. Um, how about go into a room with
Tony Jefferson and Derwin James and
Elijah Balden. I think that's a pretty
good start. Um, I just I I I love that
they were able to acrew more picks
because we we've seen Joe's track record
in his short time with the Chargers and
what they've done in rounds four to six.
Um, a lot of starters have come from
those rounds and I have no doubt that
some of those guys that were were uh had
their name called today are going to
make a big deal uh make a big uh a big
impact I think maybe this year and
beyond. Um, Brennan Thompson, if just go
back to him for a second, you know, KLS
competitors, welcome. Two speed guys.
Can't wait to see those guys go at OTAAS
in training camp.
>> Yeah. And I'll tell you the thing with
with Brennan and and Mike McDaniel is
what is what does coach McDaniel do
better than, you know, you just put them
in that same bucket, right, with Kyle
Shanahan and Shawn McVey and Matt
Laflur. But I think McDaniel might be
the best at it, and that's creating
space. And when you're a defense and you
see Brennan Thompson at 426 walk on the
field and a guy that could deal with the
physicality in the SEC and a guy that if
you want to press him and you don't get
hands on him, it's over. He and there
are a number of those where he's shaking
press and he is gone. And when you've
got a a guy that can throw it 55 yards
flatfooted that can now step into a
throw and push it 65 yards down the
field every single time he steps on the
field knowing what McDaniel can do and
creating space if you there's if you
just go and kind of watch the highlight
package of Thompson you'll see it man
he'll settle down find a soft spot whip
out and he's gone and it's over. he gets
to top speed like that. And so just and
I think that's the that's the Mike
McDaniel factor, right? Is he knows how
to get guys into crevices and and zones
that are open. And when you compare that
with 426 speed that gets to top end,
gets to 24 miles an hour in a hurry,
man, you got a defense that is now
thinking. And you know what Mike likes
to do, Coach McDaniel likes to do with
all that eye candy and what Alec Engold
said when he was at the the lectern and
like, yeah, it's a lot of nothing, but
that nothing gets people thinking and
gets them freaking out. And that's what
gets you excited about about what coach
Look, I I said this to someone today. I
had so many great conversations in the
at the bowl with fans and just people
were just I don't know they're so I
think they're combined excited about the
potential because it's Harball and it's
Herbert and you've made the playoffs and
had 11 wins back toback seasons but how
do we take how do we win this Super Bowl
and I'm freaking out and I just said
think about it man just take all the
free agents and all the draft picks off
the board if I just told you this off
seasonason you're going to get Mike
McDaniel to call your offensive plays
like how are you going to feel about the
upcoming season? Like that is
>> that is that's it. That's number one and
everything else to me is so far below
that moving forward, but they've
reinforced it with players as well.
>> I tweeted this yesterday and I think
it's worth saying again. There will be
zero starters from the loss in Foxboro
on week one. Zero starters from that
game will be starting week one against
whoever they open the season with.
back. Alt's back. Bottish is back. It'll
probably be Strange and Slaughter. Um,
even if it's Penning, it would be
Penning as a guard. Um, you have these
two guards that you drafted. Who knows
what's going to happen after the draft.
So, you're going to have a completely
different offensive line with a play
caller who was number one on the market
and the Chargers got him. Plus, Amari
and Hampton healthy. And we mentioned
Brennan Thompson speed. How about
Brennan Thompson and Keaton Mitchell on
the field at the same time?
>> Yeah. right? Like that there is like
there is real speed on this team with a
quarterback that is not afraid to get
the ball down the field, throw it into
small windows, um, and and make quick
decisions with the football. So, I just
think all of that combined, it's just a
completely different operation from last
year from an offensive perspective. I I
I don't even think you can compare it. I
don't even think you can really even
complain or talk about the offensive
line anymore because there are 14 guys
as you mentioned that are going to be
competing for starting roles and and
backup roles on this team with a new
play caller and more speed on the
outside and just the creativity of Mike
McDaniel. So, I just I I look at offense
as being a completely different
operation in 26.
>> Yeah. And I think the one thing to
remember is you just it's it's five
fingers on a glove. It's not one guy.
Now, if you have someone that, as we've
talked about, is way below average, then
a defense can figure out a way to pick
on that one weak spot. Um, but at the
same time, I just kind of think back to
how everyone felt about Zion going into
2025 and then you lose Slater and now
you've got Pipkins playing right and
you've got Alt playing left and here's
Zion who's been a punching bag and I
can't believe we're bringing this guy
back and you know on and same with
Boseman and by no means am I saying
Boseman had a good year. That's not what
I'm saying. But when you think about the
way the offense looked the first two
weeks, the first three weeks, you know,
and especially those first two weeks
against the against the Chiefs and
against the Raiders, you know, that
wasn't with Rashawn Slater and Tyler
Biottish. It was with Trey Pipkins and
Zion and Bradley Boseman and Mai
Beckton, you know, who was certainly
motivated in week one and then it
gradually tailed off from there. But
like something to remember. It's it's it
everything complements everything and
when you've got Charlie Kohler out there
and Alec Ingold out there and Omaran
Hampton like you said and you like it
it's not one left guard and that's that
is not going to unravel an offense. It's
just not you know they'll figure it out
because there's just way too much to
have Slider Slater and all pro at
Bottish in from 2022. Cole Strange who
is a former first round pick. I know he
did not did not go well in New England
but someone that was good enough in
Miami last year that McDaniel and
Bushberry Barry brought him along and al
with Kohler within gold with all of the
with Lad Mcconi and the stress that it's
going to put on defenses to see Lad out
there with with Trey Harris and like
it's 11. That's what makes football so
beautiful. This is not checkers. It is
chess. It is 11 pieces moving in
concert. They have the answer, you don't
on defense, and you're spending the 15
seconds that they line up before they
snap the ball trying to figure out what
the hell they're going to do. And the
guy that's calling the play is one of
the best at hiding from you what they're
going to do.
>> It's just not comparable at all. Like I
I think anything you saw on offense last
year, you throw it out the window. It is
not comparable at all to what you're
going to see in 2026.
Chargers Weekly is presented by
Splatero, helping homeowners access
their home equity with no monthly
payments. Split offers home equity
investments. A better way to access the
cash you need from your home without
having to go through a bank. Get a lump
sum of cash in exchange for a share of
your home's future value. Pay off debt,
renovate your home, and better your
life. Get your free cash estimate at
splotero.com/chargers.
Defensively, you know, you have a new
defensive coordinator. you get him
Messador in the first round. You knock
that out. Uh you have that that
three-headed attack. Uh you mentioned
Nick Barrett, defensive tackle. We
mentioned the uh the development of
defensive tackles here at the Chargers
with Mike and um just being able to add
to the room in in the secondary with
Genesis Smith. Um anything on defense
that you want to highlight money?
>> Yeah, I'll just start with Meador. Um I
got to spend about 25 minutes with him
today. This guy
>> a great dude, man. Oh man, I got a I got
a new favorite Charger. Like he has got
he is my kind of guy, dude. He's super
mellow and at the same time just like
very sincere and engaging and thoughtful
with his answers and he's not looking
over you or through you. Um had a great
just conversation with him. And then all
the football stuff is all football, man.
Like he is he is and and then the most
important part, right? like whatever
with what I think of his personality and
if he's, you know, my kind of guy, you
stand next to him and this guy's put
together, man. This dude is put to
together. So, it's it's a great first
round pick. And to have those three guys
knowing that that's where the defense is
going to start, you know, with that kind
of pressure with what that NASCAR
package could do last year with Owe Tuli
and and Khalil Mack and, you know, not
to mention what happened when Mack went
down and the trouble that they found
themselves in when that happened. So now
you've a got some depth, b you've
developed a boy, you know, from year one
to year two. Now you hope that year two
to year three is another jump. uh uh
Caldwell
from year one to year two. Tier Tart, we
saw the jump that he took when he got
put into a full-time Reich. All of this
stuff is is ascending. And so I think to
drop Meador in the middle into the
middle of that is that that's look they
gave Chris Ori what he needed, right?
You got to have three you got to have
that NASCAR package at your disposal.
And so, um, I think if you want to point
to one thing, it's probably corner,
right? They I think they probably could
have used a corner. And I and Joe even
acknowledged that. Um, you know, said,
"Yeah, we we were kind of looking and if
there was one at this spot, I think we
would have probably done that."
>> I wonder if McCoy would have been in the
mix had
>> he was Yeah,
>> he was. If he was if he was there with
with that first pick in the fourth
round. Yeah.
>> Yeah,
>> he was. the and I think he in talking to
some people um the from the draft, you
know, from the from all some of my old
friends at NFL Network, they were like,
"Dude, every team, the the Raiders
weren't trading that pick. Everybody had
the same plan." And they could have just
jumped up to the last pick of the third
round and done it. It would have been
the same idea. Like, you should have
thought of it last night
>> because I think the gave up a they gave
up a seventh just to move a spot ahead
of the Bills to do that. Yeah. So like
they they were willing to actually trade
a pick to get up there
and everybody wanted it. So yeah, but
that they were that was the plan.
>> Yeah. Uh so after these guys get signed,
Chargers still going to have a ton of
cap space. So that that means that you
know another move potentially a big move
is not out of the equation here in 2026.
I don't know where it would be at this
point. I think from a from a depth
perspective, you mentioned corner, but
outside of that, like I feel pretty good
about the group they're bringing in at
offensive line. I feel really good about
the wide receivers right now because I
like KLS, too. Um, I think that Brendan
Thompson and KLS with the speed. Uh, Lad
Trey taking that leap. Uh, I know that
Joe mentioned that a decision hasn't
been made on Quinton yet, but Quinton
coming in, you know, fifth year or not,
like that's it's just another weapon
that I feel like aligns nicely with Mike
McDaniel. Um, defensive tackle, feel
really good about that right now. Um,
you know, linebacker, I think we both
think Marlo Wax can be a guy this year.
Um, bringing Denzel back important. So,
Messor has a hurricane running mate in
the on on defense. But yeah, corner. I'd
have to look. I don't have the I don't
have the free agent list in front of me,
but maybe uh maybe there's a veteran
corner out there that can
>> Yeah, I don't have it up either.
>> You bring to camp.
>> Don't forget about Eric Rogers. Did you
already mention that? Did I mention
>> No, I didn't did I mention Eric Rogers,
right? So you had Eric Rogers who they
were very excited about and were willing
to carry on injury all year. Um so
you're going to have
>> Nico Reed too. Nico Reed.
>> Exactly. And Nico Reed back in the mix,
you know, into their second year. So
there is some depth there. Um but like I
said, man, I'm I'm telling you, man,
Barrett's going to I and I'm just we
were trying to figure out like how did
this guy slide? Like what what are we
missing? And there's just he was a
backup. He's a backup. his entire
college career until this last year. So,
it's only one season of production.
There's still some stuff to clean up,
but I don't know how you can watch just
the sizzle reel of this guy and see the
get off and see the moves and the
counter moves when pass rushing. Dude,
he's stacking, shedding, and wrecking
running backs. I mean, he tossed
Basantis like he was a freaking bag of
fries and made a tackle in the back
field. Like, I was like, "What the
hell?" Um, so that that I'm really and
you mentioned Genesis Smith. I think
anything that keeps Derwin James close
to the line of scrimmage to build some
depth on that back end if you know,
look, we know about Tony's age. We know
that Molden has has struggled at times
to stay healthy. So, I get taking the
the center field safety over a corner
maybe just to make sure like, hey, the
one thing we don't want to do, you got
to get out of there, Chris. They're
turning the lights out on you.
>> This happens, by the way, just as a side
note, this happens like every 25 minutes
in this office. The lights just turn
off. They turn off.
>> That's the, you know, the perils of of
weekend newsrooms, you know.
>> It's like they get no AC and the lights
get turned off on us sometimes.
>> We just finished our our inside the
draft show and we uh we featured Matt
Money Smith in at the Chargers party
with everybody having a great time. It
was awesome.
>> Yeah. So, I appreciate that. Um, but
yeah, I think just to kind of go back to
the the group as a whole, I think I just
it makes sense, right? Like I said, 50%
of your picks went to offensive line,
four of them to make sure you have some
depth. Let's get some guys we can
develop. Call them what you want. Sixth
round dark throw. Not a lot of offensive
linemen that come out of the sixth
round. I'm not going to say there are,
but there are at least some that it's
it's it's not it's not it's not nothing,
I think, is what I'm trying to say. It's
not nothing. It is something in the NFL
because we have seen undrafted and late
round picks emerge. So, to to if you can
coach them up, we just saw what they did
with Brewer in Miami, a former undrafted
guy, and they turned him into first team
all pro center. So, I'm going to put
some faith in these guys with these four
players. And if you want to have some
fun, go ahead look up the Travis Burke
sizzle reel, too. He's nasty, man. Is he
nasty.
>> I was I was I was just going to get to
him. I uh I tweeted something. Dne Dane
had him as his as a top 10 guy as a
>> and he had him at nine.
>> He had him at nine, a third round
tackle. And Dne said Travis Burke today
69 325 and a mer one of the meanest
dudes in the draft. wants to grind
defenders into the ground on every snap.
If that that's not a Jim Harbaugh guy, I
don't know who is.
>> When we uh so after the players are
picked, they set up a Zoom with the
media. So, in Travis's
uh he was asked I can't remember who
asked it. Um like what's I think it
might have been Chris Rim that asked
him. He's like, "So, what's going on,
man, when you're when you're throwing
these guys out of the back of the end
zone or driving them into the ground and
laying on them?" And he just said, "I
don't know, man. I get on that field and
and I just want to I just just it's
aggression, man. It comes out of me and
I just can't help it. I just it's just
it's what I do. And when you're that big
and you have that long of levers and you
can take advantage of people like that,
it's pretty cool. And we know it goes a
long way. um you know when you can
punish guys and you can you know sort of
inflict some you know controlled
violence on them without getting a flag.
It goes a long way and it sets a tone
and it lifts the other 10 guys that are
out there on the field up. Uh because
that's what everyone's trying to do,
right? Trying to humiliate the guy
opposite you. It's a it's a game of
violence and of controlled violence. And
so there's some fun ones in there, man.
and he took a dude right out of the back
of the end zone. I don't I think if it I
think if it was an open field, he'd
still be walking him. He'd still he'd
still have him locked up and he'd still
be walking him back. It's It's pretty
funny to watch.
>> This is why we love football. The the
juxtaposition
of Brennan Thompson and Travis Burke.
Yeah.
>> Right. Drafted back to back by the
Chargers in round four. a smaller guy
that runs 426 and an absolute giant in
Travis Burke who's just balling dudes
and throwing them out of the throwing
them out of the club. Man, it's just
this is why we love football.
>> Yeah, there are plenty of guys that are
smaller than you in the NFL, Chris.
There are not many that are smaller than
me. There are very very And I'm not
counting kickers. If I counted kickers,
there'd be a few.
>> What's your 40, money? What is your 40?
>> An afternoon. That's That's my 40. one
afternoon because guess what? If I try
to run a 40 and fire my legs, I'm going
to blow a hammy and I'm going to need to
go to the trainer table and I'm not
going to be able to to to make it to the
finish line. So that's that's what my 40
is. I learned that playing fantasy
stupid baseball camp that the radio sta
uh radio station sent me to.
>> When I freaking managed to to poke a
shot through the right side of the
infield and then ran to first base and
was like, "Ah, really?" Like that's
really going to happen there. Firing my
legs for the first time. And I remember
standing on first base, too, and the uh
the first baseman saying to me, "Uh,
hey, you're not going to take any
offense if I don't hold you on, are
you?" I was like, "No, no, not at all,
dude. I'm not stealing any bases. You
don't need to hold me on because I'm
probably not going to make it the second
in time to avoid a force out." So,
>> hey, did you hear I'm sure you heard
Rich Eisen shout you out before the
before the Brent Thompson.
>> No. What'd he say?
This the dude the dude who came to the
uh the podium. I think he was wearing a
cape and he was
>> Yeah.
>> They go, "Let's go to the podium for the
Chargers pick." He goes, "Is that Matt
Money Smith?"
>> Sounds about right.
>> You got to run it back. I think DJ was
it was Rich Charles and DJ. Oh yeah.
>> He goes, "Is that Matt Money Smith?"
>> Oh, that's great. Yeah. Hey, dude. I'
I'd be up for You know me, I love capes,
so I think I called him Count Bolto in
the uh in the press room. I love that
guy. I was I was a big fan of that guy.
It was a fun day. We were having a lot
of fun. I mean, the fact that they went
from a fourth and a sixth
>> to three fourths, a fifth, and three six
was pretty fun today, man. And it was uh
>> and they were all smiles, man. Chad and
Joe and Coach Harbaugh. Chad Alexander,
assistant GM, Joe Ortiz, general
manager, and coach Harbaugh were all
smiles in that room. And they ended up
hanging out about 105 minutes after the
press conference ended and were just
super geeked. Um, super geeked about
about the class they were able to put
together. Dude, everybody has their
passion in life and like when you see
like how elated Joe was yesterday and
today like like they they firmly believe
they crushed this thing like they they
feel really really good about what they
just did and to do it collectively. Like
Joe says we don't do it alone. Um you
know we all know uh
>> how much Chad means to to what they do
and you know how he probably won't be a
Charger very long. He'll probably be a
GM here in the next year or two. Um, but
just the scouts and everybody that makes
that thing go and the success that
they've had in in three short years with
guys we've mentioned from Gadston to
Still to Hart to Kimani Videll who was
really just kind of saved the team last
year when Hampton went out. So, um,
these guys make a big difference. So,
you know, I wouldn't be shocked if Nick
Barrett gets a huge TFL in week 16 or
Brennan Thompson has a 75 yard touchdown
against the Raiders in in November or
Travis Burke has to fill in for a game
and and uh and shuts down Max Crosby.
You never know, man. Like, these are the
guys who are going to make the
difference in 26.
>> Yeah. Yeah. And also, you know, shout
out to Cory who puts together all the
the trades. And that when you're when
you're talking about picking up, you
know, seven picks on, you know, at, you
know, getting to seven picks on day
three, uh, that's him fielding those
calls and and running that that trade
chart back and trying to figure out
where the value is and what you got to
ask for when you're on the clock and you
only got, you know, a little bit of time
to make sure that everybody's submitting
the right thing to the league so the
trade can be approved before your time
runs out and all that sort of stuff. So,
I know he was certainly busy over these
three days and uh a good job by him to
manage to get out of this thing with uh
with eight picks. Pretty cool when you
walked in with five.
>> Yeah, I think it's fun, man. I think
it's fun. It's okay to be positive about
this. I think I think that this is a uh
this is an off season where you know
free agency was a little bit slower than
maybe fans were anticipating, but I
think that you you realize after a
couple of months there's a method to the
madness and there's a reason why things
are done early and why things are done
later. And uh as Joe said, it's not over
yet. U I I have no doubt that after the
draft we're going to get some more moves
made here um as we we get up to mini
camp and eventually training camp. So,
just another another check mark. I think
the the next big checkpoint money is the
schedule release. I can't wait for that
in a couple weeks.
>> Yeah, I think May 15th, they said,
"Well, you know what? There's a big
one." And um just cuz I'm looking at the
the end of my notes here from uh from
the presser.
Uh they said, "You know what? I should
correct myself. I said they absolutely
would have taken McCoy had he been
there." Uh that may not be true because
they said that Thompson was in the mix
at 86 and that had they kept that pick,
he would have been the selection. So, I
might be wrong there. Um, I didn't want
to say that too definitively. Um, where
did it go? Oh, yeah. Q. So, May 1st is
the fifthear option decision on Q. So,
that's
>> that's coming up, you know, in a couple
days.
>> So, we're going to figure that's the
next big one is kind of whether or not
they decide. And you know, we've talked
about it and the more I think about it
with all the cap space they have, I'm
and I know it's for next year, but I
don't I don't know, man. I think I think
there's a very real possibility that
they could that they could pick it up
that they they're like, "Hey, man. Let's
just go through wide receivers that are
making 18 million bucks. If you know, we
really think Q's going to fit into
this." that could end up being a
bargain, you know, for for him and could
be a real trade chip if you want to
trade him and you got the fifth year
option there and he's making I mean, I
should actually just What the heck, man?
Let's Let's um Oh, over the
>> What is Pickkins's uh number this year?
>> 28.
>> Yeah, I'm pretty or 28 or 29. I can't
remember. Um let's see. Let's go. Uh
wide receivers.
So, uh, current APY. All right, let's
get to
let's get to 18. What was it? What's it
going to be? 18, I think. Right. So,
here's the guys. Juanale Robinson 175.
Calvin Ridley 176. Romeo Dub 17. Pitman
175.
Um, Diggs 21,
Debo 238, Pickkins is 27.3,
DJ Moore is 27.5, Jaylen Wadd 28.2,
>> like 18. You got Mike Evans,
>> money, money. Nobody's scoring more
touchdowns than Q in that range. Uh, you
know,
>> that's what I'm saying. eight, you know,
what is what is if he gets to 900 yards
and eight touchdowns again, it's
probably worth like what was the trying
to think of what the deal was that Yeah.
Josh Reynolds uh or not Josh Reynolds,
Josh Palmer. Where's Palmer at? Um did
they cut him already?
>> Who the Bills?
>> Yeah,
>> let me see.
>> I didn't remember.
Yeah, he's not on their team.
like that deal is already cooked.
>> Wow.
>> So,
yeah, I think when you look at it, like
it wouldn't surprise me. Um I still
think if if you were asking me which way
I was leaning because they drafted
Thompson, they're excited about Trey
Harris. Lad, I I would probably lean no.
And then if he has a great year, they're
happy to to get back in the mix because
they like the guy a lot. But at the same
time,
I think I don't think it's a crazy
number, as wild as that may be. And
look, I was talking to someone earlier
today in the lot. I know I keep saying
that, but like they were they were real
anti-Q. And I was like, they're like,
you know, to the point where they're
like, why you always talking them up on
Chargers Weekly? It's insincere. you
know, there's it's too inconsistent and
there's too many games where there's
>> you know, they're like, why why, you
know, there's too many games where
there's zero production and you can't
you can't celebrate them as much as you
are when the highs are high and the lows
are so low. And you know, what I just
said to her was I was like, I totally uh
you know, I understand kind of if you
look at it in totality, I was like, but
he's making two million bucks this year.
Like there's no reason to trade a guy
that's on the cap for $2 million that's
coming off back-to-back eight touchdown
seasons. Like that's worth two million
bucks and then some. And also to get a
look at him in Mike McDaniel's offense.
Like that to me, you would have had to
have been offered a two to move on from
Q at 2 million and a look see in Mike
McDaniel's offense and what he might be
able to do with him.
>> You know what, man? I I just want to say
this, like he got so much heat for the
drops and he he corrected it and he was
awesome last year and he he didn't No,
nobody said, "Oh, he he got he got
better." People still complain. I just
don't I don't know. I
>> He's an ascending player. He's not he's
not descending. He's ascending. He's
gotten better every year.
>> Yeah. So, Josh Palmer's still on the
Bills. Great job.
>> He is. Okay.
>> Thank you, Greg. Oh, there he is. Greg,
I didn't see that.
>> Uh, so he is still I don't know why I
don't have him on this here.
>> I mean, Q is is so efficient with his
targets. Like I like you you want to see
an example of what Q can do like that
Dallas game.
>> He was incredible. He was incredible in
that Dallas game. And I think it's worth
I mean, we're gonna see it this year
under Mike McDaniel, but like, you know,
I I just I wonder if if Mike McDaniel
thinks, you know what, I can
>> I can win with this guy beyond the the
five years. So, yeah, that'll be an
intriguing checkpoint too, May 1st, to
see what they do with with Quinton. And
then maybe that kind of kind of read the
tea leaves there.
>> So, here I screwed this up. I was gonna
I was I was in free agency only, so this
is even better. Uh, here we go. Dub 17,
Shahed 17, Robinson 175, Judy 175,
Pitman 175, Jacobe Meyers 20, Devonte
Adams 22, Chris Godwin 22, Courtland
Sutton 23, Nico Collins 24, Dvonte Smith
25, Jameson Williams 26.
>> Uh, Pickkins 27. Uh we went through all
of these like when 15 Cooper Cup at 15
uh Khalil Shakir at 132 like
I think I think it's possible. I I do.
I'm not I just I guess I'm setting that
up for people not to freak out if they
do pick it up and say what are they
thinking? I'm like I can kind of make
sense to it. I I can make sense of it.
>> Quinton's a really good player. Yeah,
>> Quinton's a really good player. U and I
think at 16 million that's a it's it's
pretty fair market value. It's just a
matter of, you know, if if they want to
kind of clear their books out even more
and go in a different direction. It's
it's really not so much an indictment on
on Quinton. It's just okay, you know,
this is the direction that we may want
to go with some of the guys that we're
going to bring in. So yeah, um Kandre
Lambert Smith, again, I I mentioned him
a couple of times in this podcast. I
just I feel like him and and Mike
McDaniel make sense together too. And
you know when you bring in a a speedster
like Brennan, it's just
>> just more ammunition money. Just more
ammunition for this offense. So
>> Exactly.
>> Exactly. It's compet competitors
welcome, right?
>> Competitors are always welcome.
>> You know that the idea that KLS did
enough last year to not bring in any
competition. No. Like, hey, we still
believe in you, but guess what? Earn it,
dude. You know, get out there and earn
it. This guy, Brennan Thompson, returned
one punt, one punt in his uh in his
season at Mississippi State. It was in
the bowl game, and that one punt went 44
yards. It was the last game he played.
And it's like, maybe we should have done
that a little bit more. Maybe it would
have been smart to put him back there a
little bit more. So, uh cuz they said
they were joking about it, too, when
they were asked about him. They were
like, and I That's right. You said you
watched it, so you saw it. They were
like, "Uh, yeah, are we going to put him
back there? We're going to try. Guy's
got an average of 44 yards per return.
So, uh, yes, we're gonna give that a go.
>> You know, and maybe that's maybe that's
competitors welcome with Darius Davis
back there, right?
>> Absolutely. Hey,
>> we've seen we've seen Lad back there.
>> Um, I that I think that's the theme for
me is like there's a lot of competition.
There's a lot of competition on this
roster and it's good competition because
I think I think that the guys that
they've brought in are going to be good
depth pieces as well. Um,
>> yeah,
>> I I I like I just I like the direction
of the offensive line, too. I I I think
that um you can say what you want, but
you mentioned the 14 guys that have come
in. Um we know you're getting Slater
like Joe paid Slater, right? Joe paid
Slater. So So Joe values that left side,
Joe Alt on the right side. Uh Biatish
coming in, a backup center now in
Slaughter. Um and a lot of competitors
at guard right now.
Super Bowl 61 is coming to Los Angeles
and available now, you could secure
priority access to the best seat
locations and fan experiences through On
Location, the official hospitality
provider of the NFL and proud partner of
the Los Angeles Chargers. By placing a
deposit, you'll be the first in line for
official packages that include verified
Super Bowl tickets and premium instadium
parties featuring unrivaled
entertainment and hospitality. Select
packages even include the opportunity to
celebrate on the field postgame. For
more information, visit
onloationexp.com/sup
or call 1 800591-9198.
>> I'm going to I'm going to let you have
the offense. I'm going to take the
defense. Um, coming out of today, um,
out of these last three days, I'm really
excited, man. I I think the world of
Meador and how he fits into this and,
you know, just I feel like it's a
perfect fit. And as you can tell, I'm
really excited about Barrett. Um, and I
just I think Chris Olirri watching what
he was able to do with that safety room
in his first season in the NFL coming
from Notre Dame and and where he got
Elijah Molden and and what Derwin who
was just kind of lost in the football
wilderness with everything that was
asked of him from Brandon Staley and
kind of feeling down a little bit and
not in the right place and being
recognized as one of the best not just
safeties but defensive players in the
league and for coach to for his position
coach to bring him back with Jesse Mer
to bring him back to where he deserves
to be and the conversation is, you know,
one of the best, if not the best safety
in the league along with one of the best
defensive players in the league and the
tone setter for this defense. Um, I'm I
just have a lot of faith in coach Olri
and what he's going to be able to do
because all the other position coaches,
coach Rooney and coach and coach Clink,
like they're all still there. So, you're
going to coach these guys up and and I
think they've got a lot of really really
good pieces to to work with. So, it's
look, they're coming out back toback 11
win seasons. It's a high standard to try
to measure up to that. Um, considering
the league and how, you know, how parody
reigns supreme and how hard it is to
stay consistent like that because of
free agency and people that are going to
leave to go get more money elsewhere and
the way the draft works um in reverse
order of finish. Um, but I I feel like
they got the right guys and they kept
the right guys. And you just think about
the the tracking of where Deon's going
and where Tuli is going and these
younger players are headed. Um, to
I it's it's very exciting.
>> I'll end it on offense just I I love the
collaboration between the front office
and Mike McDaniel. Mike McDaniel brings
out wanted posters of Katon Mitchell and
Alex Engold and he gets them. He asks uh
for Brennan Thompson, said he'll take
his shirt off if he get them. They got
them the next day. Mike McDaniel was
dressed so good on Thursday. I was like,
they're going offense Thursday. There's
no way this guy's not dressed for an
offensive player. But um I just I I love
the collaboration and and the
willingness to get Mike what they feel
he needs. And yeah,
>> uh you can't tell me that Jake Slaughter
wasn't part of that, right? He like Jake
Slaughter was was part of what Mike
McDaniel needs to run this offense. Um I
think that when you're drafting these
offensive linemen, you have that in
mind. Um and I just I don't think the
offense is going to look anywhere close
to what it looked like. It's just it's a
different scheme. Um, and I think you're
going to start to see these these
imprints very early with the speed that
they brought in with Mitchell and with
Thompson and I mentioned KLS and just,
you know, what we saw at the end of the
year with Trey Harris just doing a
little bit more each and every week. Uh,
we know what Quinton's capable of. I
think Lad's going to have an awesome
year as well. And just that running game
uh with uh Amarian and let's not forget
about Kimmani either. So,
>> just a lot of excitement, man. Um, I
think we're gonna have a lot to talk
about even during the dog days. Uh, you
know, with OTAAS.
>> Yeah. And I'll just to put a cap on it
because I can never let you have the
last word. I'm far too
>> narcissistic for that, Chris. Um,
like as you were as you were kind of
going through all that, it just popped
into my brain. And that is,
man, and I I probably shouldn't do this.
I don't I don't want it to come out like
it's a shot. I don't mean for it to be
that, but I mean, just think back to
last year. And I know everybody's like,
"Dude, the guy took 140 hits for God's
sakes and he was sacked 54 times." It's
like, "Well, yeah, he was taking
sevenstep drops every time he was under
freaking center. He's in shotgun and
he's taking five step drops from
shotgun." Like, that's not what this is
going to look like. Herbert is not going
to be doing that. There was almost zero
quick game last year. There were almost
zero easy buttons last year. and Mike
McDaniel majors in quick game and easy
buttons and like that's how else do you
get two out of 5,000 yards in a season.
So that's something to remember is yes,
you're you're worried about her about
Herbert and you should be, but at the
same time
that's it's it's apples to dragon fruit.
The difference I mean it's it's just not
even in the convers it's apples to
cinder blocks. there's just there's no
comparison with how Mike is coach
McDaniel is going to run this thing um
to ensure that he's just not in a
position to ever take those hits. That's
it's just a completely different
approach. Um so that's one thing to
remember as well.
>> Yeah, every listen, everybody's excited.
All 32 teams are shaking hands and and
high-fiving and feeling like they got
their guys. But I think at least with
the Chargers, we we have data and
evidence to suggest that like they have
a track record of actually finding the
guys. Like we we've seen it the last
couple of years here.
>> Yeah. I'm trying to figure out if we uh
if we if we have do we have any grades?
Do we have any grades on the uh the
draft class? Let's see if our friends
over at uh at the Athletic have graded
the draft. Well, that's a good headline
for Popper. Did the Chargers just fill
every major need? Um, that's his
headline.
>> Yeah,
>> I think we said they did except for
maybe corner, right? I think that was
the only position.
>> Exactly. Here we go. Drafts. No, that's
uh grades for two and three. So, not
yet. See what we get on the grades from
the people that uh that want everyone to
abide by their draft board as opposed to
the one they have in their room.
>> Exactly. All right, I gotta go. Uh I
gotta go on set, do some sports hits.
Uh, buddy, have a great weekend, man.
>> I got to go see Smokeoky and the Bandit
at the Bay Theater here in Seal Beach.
That's what I got to do, baby. My
favorite movie of all time. And I I mean
that literally. It is my favorite film
of all time. So, uh, the wife and I
going to go check it out at 7:00. Cannot
wait.
>> All right, man. We'll go to it. Enjoy
it. Uh, for money, I'm Chris. This has
been Chargers Weekly. We'll see you next
week.